ADIVIA GILANG PRAKARSA

FRONTEND ENGINEER

□ (+62) 81261840233 | adivia9p@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/adiviagp



Summary_

Diligent software engineer with 4+ years of experience in web development. I'm an enthusiastic, responsible, and hardworking person. I'm able to work well both in a team environment as well as using my own initiative. Enthusiastic in continuous learning and proactive in taking up the tasks.

Education

UNIVERSITAS ISLAM INDONESIA

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

BACHELOR OF INFORMATIC ENGINEERING (GPA 3.72)

Sep, 2017 - Jan. 2021

Design thinking, Programming logic, Fundamentals of application development, Algorithms and data structure, Software
engineering, Web based application development, Information technology development management, Fundamentals of
informatic, Software architecture.

Skills

LANGUAGES Javascript, Typescript, PHP, C#

TECHNOLOGIES React. js, Next. js, Redux, Context API, React Native, GraphQL, Vue. js, Laravel, ASP.NET, Express js, Git

Work Experience _____

PT BFI Finance Indonesia Tbk

Tangerang, Indonesia

FRONTEND ENGINEER - CONTRACT UNDER SIGMA TECH

May. 2022 - May, 2024

- Collaborate with product team, development teams, and other stakeholders to build new user features and drive the frontend technology stack forward
- Ensure the delivery of high-quality solutions by implementing a comprehensive testing strategy that includes unit, and acceptance tests
- Fixing any issues or bugs that arise

ONEBYONE LOGISTICAL pty. ltd

Batam, Indonesia

FULLSTACK ENGINEER - CONTRACT

Sep. 2021 - Apr. 2022

- Develop and design RESTful services and APIs using ASP.NET
- Working with external Product Team to developed inventory module for Japan client
- Taking lead on integration projects collaborating with internal Engineer and Business Analyst
- · Updating React component, as needed

JALA TECH pte. ltd

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

FRONTEND ENGINEER - INTERN

Apr. 2020 - Sep. 2020

- Build reusable component for future using Vue.js
- Implement user interface with highly functional, lightweight, responsive based on UI design and backend APIs.
- · Collaborate with multidisciplinary team of designers, and engineers

FLOBEE Software House

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

FULLSTACK ENGINEER - PART TIME

Feb. 2019 - Jul. 2021

- Define and communicate technical requirements
- Develop functional and sustainable web applications with Laravel and Vue.js
- Provide training, help and support to clients

LABORATORY ASSISTANT - UNIVERSITAS ISLAM INDONESIA

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

WEB BASED APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT - PART TIME

Aug. 2019 - Jan. 2020

- · Assists lecturers in the teaching process
- Helps students learn to develop web app using PHP, Javascript and Laravel framework.
- · Actively doing guidance and tutorials to increase student understanding of these courses

LABORATORY ASSISTANT - UNIVERSITAS ISLAM INDONESIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING - PART TIME

Yogyakarta, Indonesia Mar. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Assists lecturers in the teaching process
- Helps students learn how to build systems with the right method and great timeline, and also documenting the systems.

BINAR ACADEMY

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

BACKEND DEVELOPER STUDENT - PART TIME

Feb. 2019 - Jul. 2019

- Define and communicate technical requirements
- Develop REST API using Ruby on rails
- Collaborate with Frontend and Mobile Engineers.

Licenses & Certifications

- 2021 Codecademy, Create an Advanced Web App with React and Redux Skill Path
- 2018 Hacktiv8 x Developer circle, Javascript Development Course

Honors & Awards

2019 **2rd Place**, National Informatic Competition (Web Application) Universitas Negeri semarang

Semarang

2018 Finalist, Dilo Hackathon Festival

Yogyakarta